<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resume>

	<contact>
		<name>Kevin J. McIntyre</name>
		<address>Palo Alto, CA</address>
		<phone>(714) 642-9024</phone>
	</contact>

	<skill title="Servers">
		<list>
				Apache, Express, Jboss, Nginx, Tomcat, Wordpress
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="Data">
		<list>
				Aurora, Cassandra, DynamoDB, MongoDB, MSSQL, MySQL, Oracle, Postgres, Redis
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="Domains">
		<list>
		    Android, AWS, Hibernate, J2EE, JQuery, JSON, Node, PHP, Python,
		    Qt, Rest, SecXML, Spring, Twisted, WebSocket, Web Services, XML/XSLT
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="Tools">
		<list>
			ADT, CircleCI, Eclipse, Jenkins, Jira, Junit, Maven, WebDriver
		</list>
	</skill>

	<header title="Objective">
		<description>
			Seeking role as principal/lead engineer, or hands-on development manager.
		</description>
	</header>

	<header title="Summary">
		<description>
			Full stack developer, predominantly within AWS ecosystem, focused on enabling best-in-bread open source technologies to perform as designed.
		</description>
		<description>
			A proponent of full system CICD, and giving developers opportunities to be highly productive within gracefully failing guardrails.
		</description>
		<description>
			As a member of a team and part of an organization, I've always tried to be a fun dependable co-worker. Interests include water sports, cycling, green tea, and NFL.
		</description>
		<workpic image="work.png"/>
	</header>

	<highlight image="freelancers.jpeg">
		Poineered health care benefits portal/EDI processing and generation platform sufficiently dynamic
		to support Obamacare requirements, multiple vendor changes and SSO integrations.
	</highlight>
	<highlight image="quickbooks.png">
		Fostered an events library for Quickbooks enrollment of which large pieces are still operational.
		Incubated Wordpress/AWS publishing platform supporting a myriad of content needs.
	</highlight>
	<highlight image="athleets.png">
		Founder of athleets.com a social contextual app featuring real-time identity valadation tools.
		Authored as a suite of services across a multitude of AWS systems.
	</highlight>

	<job>
		<tenure image="cognizant.png">
			<title>Principal Fullstack Engineer</title>
			<company>Cognizant</company>
			<begin>Oct 2019</begin>
		</tenure>
		<story>
			UI engineer for <linkto url="macys.com">Macys</linkto> authoring
			Backbonejs, Marionettejs, Webpack components with corresponding test
			written in Karma Runner.  Contibutor on Java Spring/Java Jersey backend proxy.
			<break/>
			<break/>
			Fullstack engineer for <linkto url="walmart.com">Walmart</linkto>
			authoring components related to inbound receiving Cordova app
			supported by CXF/Spring/Camel backend integrated with Kafka
			and IBM MQ.
			<break/>
			Brought testing expertise using Puppeteer, as well as javax validation
			utilization to reduce code and test complexity. Promonent for MOB programming
			sessions bringing together all team members to facilitate learning across
			platform.  Worked across Walmart ecocystem incorpating Grafana, xMatters,
			and other in-house reporting systems.
		</story>
	</job>
	<job>
		<tenure image="quickbooks.png">
			<title>Senior Engineer</title>
			<company>Intuit</company>
			<begin>Jan 2017</begin>
			<end>May 2019</end>
		</tenure>
		<story>
			Architect of <linkto url="wordpress.org">Wordpress</linkto> infrastructure hosting marketing sites
			<linkto url="quickbooks.intuit.com">QuickBooks</linkto>, <linkto url="www.intuit.com">Intuit</linkto>, <linkto url="www.tsheets.com">TSheets</linkto> and
			<linkto url="www.firmofthefuture.com">FirmOfTheFuture</linkto>.
			Member of Intuit Innovation Catalyst group promoting Intuit customer obsession principals such as Design for Delight.
			<break/>
			CICD workflows using CircleCI across a suite of Git repositories, supporting Wordpress plugin, theme, and component releases.
			CloudFormation infrastructure templates/deployment scripts utilizing Aurora DB, multiple LC/ASG, Lambda, Lambda@Edge, CloudWatch, SNS/SQS, SSM Manager, and custom AIM formation.
			Wordpress plugin development supporting CDN cache invalidation, static publishing and custom WP-JSON integrations.
			Web-component development using Composer, Webpack, Gatbsy, React, and AngularJS in support of a myriad of marketing needs as part of migration from AEM to Wordpress.
			Developer on Intuit Iris messaging platform.
			<break/>
			Migration from Spring 1.3 to Spring 1.6, Guava to Caffine cache management, and update of critical maven dependencies.
			Extended MQ/Kafka bridge library to support additional messaging schema types and brokering strategies.  Added integration testing, Spring Boot dynamic endpoint configuration.
			Prototyped email delivery via AWS Pinpoint.
			<break/>
			Lead developer on subsequent version of Quickbooks registration workflow.
			Reduced code complexity from 13K to 9K lines of code, and release time from hours to minutes by migration of bulky Ruby on Rails endpoints to AWS Node/Express based services.
			Migrated from Perforce to Git, implemented Jenkins workflow targeting Adobe Experience Manager bundle with Selinum and Hobbes.js validation.
			Splunk dashboading to isolate registration dropoff, customer pain-points, and internal service errors.
			Worked with regional product teams for GDPR compliance.
		</story>
	</job>
	<job>
		<tenure image="nike.png">
			<title>Consultant</title>
			<company>Nike</company>
			<begin>Jan 2016</begin>
			<end>Dec 2016</end>
		</tenure>
		<story>
			Full-stack engineer on Nike Present IOS application.
			Implemented new features on web-application backend running on Tomcat, Spark, MongoDB with Spock/Groovy tests.
			Application refresh with Angular/Material Design upgrade, and enhanced Protractor testing.
			IOS Swift upgrade with security refactor aligning with corporate directives.
			MongoDB upgrade, and additional stack tuning via ThoughtWorks Go pipeline updates.
			AEM development of AEM media workflows.
		</story>
	</job>
	<job>
		<tenure image="quickbooks.png">
			<title>Software Consultant</title>
			<company>Intuit</company>
			<begin>Nov 2014</begin>
			<end>Oct 2015</end>
		</tenure>
		<story>
			Consultant on embedded javascript widget for Quickbooks registration workflow.
			RequireJS bundle using event driven model for trail/purchase funnels featuring de-coupled internationalization and localization modules.
			Mustache templating integration with AEM components allowing customized registration experiences to be authored.
		</story>
	</job>
	<job>
		<tenure image="esri.png">
			<title>Consultant</title>
			<company>Esri</company>
			<begin>Mar 2013</begin>
			<end>Aug 2013</end>
		</tenure>
		<story>
			Architect on ecommerce portion of <linkto url="developers.arcgis.com">ArcGIS for Developers</linkto>.
			Multi-tiered maven project bridging <linkto url="www.salesforce.com/us/developer/docs/api/index.htm">Salesforce API</linkto> with
			Spring and Java Jersey.
			AWS components inlcuded Amazon ElastiCache, Elastic Beanstalk capable of supporting 5000 simultaneous registrations.
			Test driven development using TestNG, Spring Test within Jenkins CICD pipeline.
			Worked with offsite engineering team to coordinate UI releases and shared testing libraries.
		</story>
	</job>

	<job>
		<tenure image="gcn.png">
			<title>Lead Developer</title>
			<company>Green Charge Networks</company>
			<begin>Aug 2011</begin>
			<end>Apr 2013</end>
		</tenure>
		<story>
			Developer on products Greenstation, and GridSynergy for <linkto url="www.greenchargenet.com">Green Charge Networks</linkto>.
			Lead development on prototype of event-driven embedded battery management system controller using <linkto url="twistedmatrix.com">Twisted</linkto>.
			Real-time charting system using Redis, and Google Visualization.
			Developer on network operation J2EE software Tomcat, Hibernate, Spring, and Google Web Toolkit.
		</story>
	</job>

	<job>
		<tenure image="freelancers.jpeg">
			<title>Java Architect</title>
			<company>Freelancers Union</company>
			<begin>Apr 2008</begin>
			<end>Feb 2011</end>
		</tenure>
		<story>
			Lead developer on a <linkto url="www.freelancersinsuranceco.com/">medical portal</linkto> for the Freelancers Union.
			Implemented project using Eclipse, SVN, Maven, Xdoclet, MantisBT targeting
			Linux/CentOS running Apache, Jboss 4.2.3, and Oracle 11g.
			Application featured services that serialized third-party <linkto
			url="en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_Data_Interchange">EDI</linkto> file
			into a data warehouse.
			SSO modules to view patient claims information on third-party websites written in OpenSAML and SAML 2.0.
			Key contributor to 3rd party vendor analysis and selection.
		</story>
	</job>

	<job>
		<tenure>
			<title>Consultant</title>
			<company>NYC</company>
			<begin>Oct 1996</begin>
			<end>Mar 2008</end>
		</tenure>
		<story>
			Consultant to variety of companies both Fortune 500 and new media.
			Engineered enterprise Swing application for an industry leading
			health club chain <linkto url="www.crunch.com">Crunch Fitness</linkto>.
			Software development at <linkto url="www.iamplify.com">Iamplify.com</linkto>, responsible for content delivery platform and ecommerce
			<linkto url="www.oscommerce.com">OSCommerce</linkto> fulfillment.
			Consultant to <linkto url="blueprint.com">Blueprint</linkto>, a pharmaceutical branding company, responsible for web application connecting doctors and patients.
			Lead developer on automated probationer check-in system for NYC Department of Probation.
		</story>
	</job>

</resume>
