<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resume>

	  <contact>
			<name>Kevin J. McIntyre</name>
			<phone>(714) 642-9024</phone>
			<email>kevin70@yahoo.com</email>
	  </contact>

    <header>
    <description/>
		</header>
	<header>
		<description>
			 In response to Sr. Software Engineer, Backend posted on
			 <linkto url="slack.com/careers/2349830/sr-software-engineer-backend">slack</linkto>.
		</description>
		<br/><br/>
		<description>
			 Hello Slack!  First off, I want to commend the organization on providing a world class
			 product, that raises the productivity of users wherever I've had the pleasure of working that uses slack.
			 Channel based communication is the way forward, and an open platform that allows for
			 developers to build tools for other developers enriches the software development community.
			 Countless times during hack-a-thons the best product is invariably a slack app furthering
			 developer engagement.
		</description>
		<br/><br/>
		<description>
			 I'm a generalist with knowledge up and down the stack, having architected and developed on numerous systems across many business needs.
			 In particular, I cite my work at Intuit; architecting Wordpress platform on AWS, authoring plugins and components, and working with
			 developers/content-creators to increase the organization's velocity.
		</description>
		<br/><br/>
		<description>
			 Additionally I cite my work on my side project Athleets.com where I endeavored to bring
			 contextualization to professional athletes tweets while I taught myself the AWS ecosystem
			 from a pure curiousity standpoint.  During this time I learned core AWS offerings to a depth
			 that goes beyond professional usage.  I emerged from this period very knowledgeable in how to
			 build economical systems and the ability to solve problems via novel means.
		</description>
		<br/><br/>
		<description>
			 I have a passion for software development with an approach that's similar to yoga.
			 It's a practise that's to be performed everyday.  How can I/we
			 get better day to day?  I thrill in the working with others, creating that
			 collective mindspace where groups of individuals are executing code in our
			 thoughts.  Encouraging each other to try new things, and recognizing efforts large
			 and small that make for great teams.
		</description>
		<description>
			Thanks again for a great product, that's made my life easier.  And thank you
			for any time/consideration given on my behalf.
		</description>
	</header>
	<header>
		<description>
		Kevin McIntyre
		</description>
	</header>

</resume>
